EDWARD HARRIS

Full-stack web developer who's highly driven and a fast learner; experience with Frontend and Backend development. Unique background with 5+ years of experience in legal field; demonstrating attention-to-detail, end-to-end project management skills and ability to effectively self-manage in independent projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRONT-END LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SASS, TypeScript

BACK-END LANGUAGES: JQuery, C#, ASP.NET, MySQL

FRAMEWORKS & MORE: Angular, React, Bootstrap, Git, Unit Testing, MSTest, Karma, Jasmine,

Firebase, Gulp, Webpack, Github

PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS

GITHUB: https://github.com/harriseim

SEAHAWKS.COM RECREATION (ANGULAR)

Github: https://github.com/harrisejm/JavaScript-Seahawks.com

Live Site: https://seahawks-311da.firebaseapp.com/

+ Recreated fully functional Seahawks.com responsive website with Angular, including mock articles, videos and the ability for users to leave comments on each article/video (saves to Google Firebase).

ONLINE CHESS GAME (REACT)

Github: https://github.com/harrisejm/chess-beta- Live Site: https://github.com/harrisejm/chess-beta-

- + Two players can play against each other on different devices. Fully playable online.
- + Only allows legal moves and includes all rules: piece movements, castling, piece detection, promotion of pawns, tests for all check and checkmate scenarios and conditions.

MINESWEEPER GAME (REACT)

Github: https://github.com/harrisejm/Minesweeper Live Site: https://minesweeper-edward-harris.web.app

- + Classic Minesweeper game. Includes beginner, medium and expert mode.
- + Records and displays high scores.

WORK EXPERIENCE 10/2018 - 12/2018

WEB DEVELOPER INTERN - Off The Record

- + Developed and implemented new features for the attorney portal website using Angular JS.
- + Implemented responsive web design. Fixed bugs in existing web pages in 1 day that improved web functionality and speed.

05/2018 - 10/2018

FULL-STACK DEVELOPMENT STUDENT - Epicodus

- + Spent 5 months coding 8 hours a day in JavaScript, Angular, React, C#, ASP.NET Core and other web development technologies.
- + Developed web app with C# and MySQL that allows users to add new stylists to a list of current employees at their salon. The user can also add individual clients to a list for each stylist, as well as the stylist's specialties.

2014 - 2018

PARALEGAL – Flynn Law Group

+ Assisted attorneys in providing defensive strategies for employers in matters pertaining to workers' compensation. Coordinated and implemented collection strategies to recoup overpaid workers' compensation benefits.

2014

PARALEGAL - Olive | Bearb, Grelish & Gilbert

+ Assisted attorneys in resolving legal matters pertaining to personal injuries.

2012 - 2014

PARALEGAL - Reinisch Wilson Weier, PC.

+ Assisted attorneys in providing defensive strategies for employers in matters pertaining to workers' compensation.

EDUCATION

2006 - 2011

WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY, B.A. Psychology